♪ Led through the mist ♪
♪ by the milk light of moon ♪
♪ all that was lost is revealed ♪
♪ our long-bygone burdens ♪
♪ mere echoes of the spring ♪
♪ but where have we come ♪
♪ and where shall we end? ♪
♪ if dreams can't come true ♪
♪ then why not pretend? ♪
♪ how the gentle wind ♪
♪ beckons through the leaves ♪
♪ as autumn colors fall ♪
Somewhere lost in the clouded annals of history
lies a place that few have seen...
a mysterious place called th{ Unknown,
where long-forgotten stories are revealed to those
who travel through the wood.
...Antelope, Guggenheim,
Albert, Salami, Giggly, Jumpy, Tom, Thomas, Tambourine,
Leg face McCullen, Artichoke, Penguin, Pete, Steve,
but I think the very worst name for this frog is...
Wait. Wait a second. Uh, Greg...
...where are we?
In the woods.
I mean
what are we doing out here?
We're walking home.
Greg, I think we're lost.
We sh... we should have left a trail or something.
I can leave a trail of candy from my pants.
No.
Though I am lost, my wounded heart resides back home,
in pieces, strewn about the graveyard of my lost love,
for only...
Huh! Do you hear that?
Yeah.
Do you think it's some kind of deranged lunatic with an ax
waiting out there in the darkness for innocent victims?
Greg. Greg!
Greg, you're gonna get us into trouble again.
We should ask him for help.
No, we should not ask him for help.
- But...
- Shh!
You shush.
- You shush.
- Shh.
Shoot.
You think we should have asked him for help?
Maybe I can help you?
I mean, you guys are lost, right?
What in the world is going on?
Well, you're slapping yourself
and I'm answering your question and...
No, Greg. A bird's brain isn't big enough for cognizant speech.
Hey, what was that?
I mean, I'm just saying you're... you're weird...
like, not normal. I-I mean..
Oh, my gosh. Stop talking to it, Wirt.
"It"?
Uh... uh...
What are you doing here?!
Explain yourselves!
And I'll see you guys later. Bye.
Calm... calm down, mister.
Wh-Whatever you do here is your business.
We just want to get home
with all of our legs and arms attached.
These woods are no place for children.
Don't you know the beast is afoot here?
The beast?
W-W-W-We don't know anything about that.
W-We're just two lost kids trying to get home.
Well, welcome to the Unknown, boys.
You're more lost than you realize.
I found this homestead abandoned
and re-purposed its mill for my needs.
You and your brother should be safe here, while I work.
Candy trail, candy trail, candy trail.
What... what is your work, exactly?
Everyone has a torch to burn,
and this here's mine.
I grind the horrid edelwood trees
into oil to keep this lantern lit.
This is my lot in life.
This is my burden.
This guy sounds loony.
Maybe we should make a break for it, if we can.
But he must know the woods really well
so we may need to knock him out first
Except that may turn out really badly, huh?
Yeah, bad... bad plan.
- Forget it. Bad plan.
- Okay.
What are you boys whispering about?
We're talking about running away out of here.
Shh! Shh!
- Shh!
Leave if you wish. But remember...
the beast haunts these woods,
ever singing his mournful melody
in search of lost souls such as yourselves!
- To help us?
- No, not to help you.
I have work to do in the mill.
When I am finished, I will do what I can to guide you
if you are still here when I return.
Huh, I guess we could just leave.
But I don't know.
Greg!
What?
Do you really think there is a beast out there?
Or is that guy just messing with us?
Uh huh.
I mean, he could have done away with us by now if that was his plan
and he lit that fire.
- That's pretty nice.
- Yeah!
I guess it's possible there's a beast,
since there was a talking bird, but...
- Yeah!
I don't know.
Sometimes I feel like I'm just like...
a boat upon a winding river,
twisting towards an endless black sea...
further and further
drifting away from where I want to be,
who I want to be.
Oh. I didn't know that.
Did you know that if you soak a raisin in grape juice, it turns into a grape?
It's a rock fact!
You're not helping at all.
Why don't you go play with your frog or something?
Aw, beans!
Where is that frog o' mine?
Hold on there, second brother o' mine.
I'll be back soon for your plan.
Kitty? Kitty!
Now, where did that frog named "Kitty" go?
Whoop!
I tripped on my own candy trail!
Huh?
graawr
That frog's giving me the runaround.
Kitty!
Gross.
graawr
Kitty?
Hmm. Is that...
Whoop!
Oh, there you are!
graawr
Wirt?
Kitty?
You have beautiful eyes.
Greg?
Uh...
What's happening?!
Where's your brother?!
Uh-uh-uh.
Holy moly. Hot dog.
It's the beast!
Stay back, boys!
This creature which is known as...
Huh?
Ohhh.
Greg, why did you do that?!
That was your plan, remember?
Knock him out!
No! Bad plan!
I told you to forget that plan!
Spank! Spank! Spank!
Run, run, run, run, run, run, run!
Candy camouflage!
Run, run, run, run, run, run, run, run.
- Greg!
- This is amazing, huh?!
Am I supposed to throw something?
Oof.
Oh, yeah!
Ha ha!
He's eating your candy.
I wonder if he ate my whole candy trail that led to this mill.
Ugh! Greg
you led the beast right to us with your candy!
Hey, give me the ax.
You're too little to have it anyway. I-
Ahhh, w-we got to get out of here!
Ah! Uh, Greg, give him the rest of your candy!
Oops.
Hey, Wirt, look!
Greg?
Wirt, he spit up that turtle, and now he's my new best friend!
Ohh! Ohh.
Hey, where are you going?
Ain't that just the way...
The mill is destroyed. The oil...
all gone!
But... but... but look. We got the beast problem solved.
The dog?! That is not the beast!
The beast cannot be mollified like some farmer's pet!
He stalks like the night.
He sings like the four winds.
He is the death of hope.
He steals their children,
and he'll... ruin...
You're always messing up, Greg.
Boy!
you have it backwards!
You are the elder child!
You are responsible for you and your brother's actions!
I'm... I'm... I'm sorry. Maybe I can... fix it?
I-I can't fix it.
You must go.
Take your brother North. Look for a town.
Yeah. Thanks. Come on, Greg.
One last thing.
beware the Unknown!
Fear the beast and leave these woods...
if you can.
It is your burden to bear!
Right. Yeah. Got it.
And, little one, you look after that frog.
Give him a proper name.
graawr
Okay.
Wirt, I think I thought of a new name for our frog.
I'm gonna call him "Wirt."
That's gonna be really confusing.
No, I'm gonna call you "Kitty."
What?!
Maybe I'll start calling you "candy pants."
Whoa! Yeah!
graawr
Good one, Wirt.
Thanks.
I'm not talking to you.
I'm talking to Wirt.